Muhammad Fadhlurrohman Faqih

Cilegon, Banten | 0822-4214-9276 | mffadhlurrohmanfaqih@gmail.com Linkedin | Github

SUMMARY

I have 1-year experience of working as a lubricant engineer at PT. Indah Kiat Pulp & Paper, Tbk. I also have 4 months of experience working as an engineer at PT. KPDP. My passion lies in the field of data analysis and data science, as well as statistics. I possess a strong understanding of programming languages such as Python, R and some knowledge of SQL. With a strong passion for data science, I aspire to further develop and build my career in this field.

EXPERIENCE

PT. INDAH KIAT PULP & PAPER - Serang, Indonesia

Lubricant Engineer (January 2022 - December 2022)

- Has a responsibility to maintain machine performance using preventive methods.
- Taking care of machine lubricant quality and success to reduce machine downtime by 1% each month.
- Collaborate with teams from each department to ensure no abnormal conditions in all machines.
- Leader and person in charge of the long shutdown project, has a responsibility to maintain, manage, supervise, and make a work plan. Successfully completed all the projects before the deadline.

PT. KPDP - Cilegon, Indonesia

Engineer (August 2018 - November 2018)

- Collaborate with any stakeholder to make sure every job is done under target.
- Maintain machine support system quality and lifetime in the form of hydraulic and pneumatic systems.
- Has the responsibility to manage teams and make sure to make a safe work environment.

PT. Krakatau Steel – Cilegon, Indonesia

Intern (January 2016 – March 2016)

- Learn how to identify failure machine potential and how to handle it.
- Learn how to make decisions based on daily machine reports and creates work plans as output.

EDUCATION

ALGORITMA DATA SCIENCE SCHOOL (January 2023 - April 2023)

Data Scientist Student - 128/140

JEMBER UNIVERSITY (January 2019 - June 2021)

Bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering – 3.11

DIPONEGORO UNIVERSITY (August 2014 - April 2018)

Associate's degree in Mechanical Engineering – 2.97

CERTIFICATIONS

- Algoritma Data Science School
- Udemy Statistic for Data Science and Business Analysis

SKILLS

- Analytical Thinking
- Critical Thinking
- Communication Skills
- Teamwork
- Project Management
- Fast Learner
- Collaborative

- Data Preprocessing
- Machine Learning: Random Forest, Decision Tree, Time Series, Regression, Classification
- Data Visualization: Tableau, R Studio